George and Ira Gershwin Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Correspondence (Box 63-66)
  - Mosbacher, Emil
    - 1936 September 22 (Box-folder 64/41)
  - Mower, Margaret
    - 1928 August 24 (Box-folder 64/42)
  - Music Publishers Holding Corp.
    - 1942, 1948 April 15 (Box-folder 64/43)
    - 1948 April 19 (Box-folder 64/44)
    - 1948 April 21, 1955 (Box-folder 64/45)
  - Nadige, Countess De Ganny
    - 1928 July 27 (Box-folder 64/46)
  - Nat [Surname not given]
    - 1927 June 7 (Box-folder 64/47)
  - National Association of Performing Arts
    - 1937 July 27 (Box-folder 64/48)
  - Noguchi, Isamu
    - 1933-36 (Box-folder 64/49)
  - O'Brien Jean
    - 1927 August 10 (Box-folder 64/50)
  - Paley, Emily
    - 1934 July 11 (Box-folder 64/51)
    - 1937 March 16 (Box-folder 64/52)
  - Pallay, George
    - 1931 April 14 [Incomplete; p. 1 only] (Box-folder 64/53)
    - 1931 August 15 (Box-folder 64/54)
    - 1931 October 5 (Box-folder 64/55)
    - 1931 October 19 (Box-folder 64/56)
    - 1932 March 8 (Box-folder 64/57)
    - 1933 September 23 (Box-folder 64/58)
    - 1934 February 26 (Box-folder 64/59)
    - 1937 July (Box-folder 64/60)
  - Pallay, George to Pringle, Aileen
    - 1937 or later (Box-folder 64/61)
  - Philadelphia Grand Opera Co.
    - 1931 April 18 (Box-folder 64/62)
    - 1931 April 26 - November (Box-folder 64/63)
  - Porgy and Bess (Blevins Davis Prod.): Publicity
    - 1955 (Box-folder 64/64)
  - Pringle, Aileen
    - 1930 November (Box-folder 64/65)
    - 1931 January 30 (Box-folder 64/66)
    - 1931 March 2 (Box-folder 64/67)
    - 1931 March 25 (Box-folder 64/68)
    - 1931 June 30 (Box-folder 64/69)
    - 1931 August 17 (Box-folder 64/70)
    - 1931 November 23 (Box-folder 64/71)
    - 1931 December 25 (Box-folder 64/72)
    - 1931 December 31 (Box-folder 64/73)
    - 1932 January 29 (Box-folder 64/74)
    - 1932 December 23 (Box-folder 64/75)
  - Reiner, Fritz
    - 1942 November 21 (Box-folder 64/76)
  - Rosenthal, Mildred
    - 1934 June 13 (Box-folder 64/77)
  - Ruby, Harry
    - 1960 September 15 (Box-folder 64/78)
  - Schillinger, Joseph
    - 1933 August 9 (Box-folder 64/79)
  - Schirmer, Mabel
    - 1926 March 6 (Envelope only) (Box-folder 64/80)
    - 1928 February 28 (Box-folder 64/81)
    - 1936 September 1 (Box-folder 64/82)
    - 1936 September 18 (Box-folder 64/83)
    - 1936 October 28 (Box-folder 64/84)
    - 1936 December 3 (Box-folder 64/85)
    - 1936 December 31 (Box-folder 64/86)
    - 1937 February 9 (Box-folder 64/87)
    - 1937 April 20 (Box-folder 64/88)
    - 1937 May 19 (Box-folder 64/89)
  - Sirmay, Albert
    - 1929-30 (Box-folder 65/1)
    - 1935 February (Box-folder 65/2)
    - 1935 [Undated] (Box-folder 65/3)
    - 1936 September 8 (Box-folder 65/4)
    - 1936 November 24 (Box-folder 65/5)
    - 1937 March 15 (Box-folder 65/6)
    - 1937 April 29 (Box-folder 65/7)
    - 1937 September 11 (Box-folder 65/8)
    - 1952 May 20 (Box-folder 65/9)
  - Starr, J.D.
    - 1933 November 21 (Box-folder 65/10)
  - Steindler, Emanuel
    - 1936 December 11 (Box-folder 65/11)
  - Steinway and Sons
    - 1931 August 28 (Box-folder 65/12)
  - Stevens, Carol to Rose Gershwin
    - 1937 June 30 (Box-folder 65/13)
  - Sutton, Horace
    - 1958 September 10 (Box-folder 65/14)
    - 1958 October 20 (Box-folder 65/15)
  - Swift, Kay (to Emily Paley)
    - 1937 July 11 (Box-folder 65/16)
  - Swift, Kay
    - 1946 October 1 (Box-folder 65/17)
    - 1949 January 6 (Box-folder 65/18)
    - 1965 March 30 (Box-folder 65/19)
    - 1965 December 2 (Box-folder 65/20)
    - 1966 July 12 (Box-folder 65/21)
  - Tamber, Selma
    - 1936 September 19 (Box-folder 65/22)
    - 1936 September 30 (Box-folder 65/23)
    - 1936 December 5 (Box-folder 65/24)
    - 1936 December 23 (Box-folder 65/25)
    - 1937 March 20 (Box-folder 65/26)
    - 1937 May 12 (Box-folder 65/27)
    - Thursday [Undated] (Box-folder 65/28)
  - Terrell, St. John
    - 1966 October 21 (Box-folder 65/29)
  - Tirana, Rosamond Walling
    - 1927-28 September 25 (Box-folder 65/30)
    - 1928 September (Box-folder 65/31)
    - 1929 before January 19 (Box-folder 65/32)
    - 1929 January 19 (Box-folder 65/33)
    - 1929 January 29 - February 2 (Box-folder 65/34)
    - 1929 February 7 or 14 (Box-folder 65/35)
    - 1929 late February (Box-folder 65/36)
    - 1929 March 1 (Box-folder 65/37)
    - 1929 March 9 (Box-folder 65/38)
    - 1929 April 29 (Box-folder 65/39)
    - 1929 late April? - May 14? (Box-folder 65/40)
    - 1929 May 19 (Box-folder 65/41)
    - 1929 July 4 - October 6 (Box-folder 65/42)
    - 1929 October 10 (Box-folder 65/43)
    - 1929 November 6 (Box-folder 65/44)
    - 1929 November 21 (Box-folder 65/45)
    - 1930 January 29 - February 7 (Box-folder 65/46)
    - 1930 February 15 (Box-folder 65/47)
    - 1930 February 18 or 25 - March 12 (Box-folder 65/48)
    - 1930 March 21 (Box-folder 65/49)
    - 1930 March 21 - April 19 (Box-folder 65/50)
    - 1930 April 24 (Box-folder 65/51)
    - 1930 April 30 (Box-folder 65/52)
    - 1930 May 10 (Box-folder 65/53)
    - 1930 May 11 - 18 (Box-folder 65/54)
    - 1930 June 3 (Box-folder 65/55)
    - 1930 June? - July 10 (Box-folder 65/56)
    - 1930 July 17 (Box-folder 65/57)
    - 1930 late July - August 6 (Box-folder 65/58)
    - 1930 August 29 (Box-folder 65/59)
    - 1930? summer - October 28? (Box-folder 65/60)
    - 1931 January 19 (Box-folder 65/61)
    - 1931 January 31 (Box-folder 65/62)
    - 1931 June 17 - July 8 (Box-folder 65/63)
    - 1931 July 12 (Box-folder 65/64)
    - 1931 July 18 - 29 (Box-folder 65/65)
    - 1931 August 3 (Box-folder 65/66)
    - 1931 September 5 (Box-folder 65/67)
  - Tirana, Rosamond Walling (on Goldberg: George Gershwin dust jacket)
    - 1931 early September (Box-folder 65/68)
  - Tirana Rosamond Walling
    - 1931 September 24 - 1933 March 1 (Box-folder 65/69)
    - Undated, before 1937 (Box-folder 65/70)
    - 1947 October 29, 1959 January 6 - 22 (Box-folder 65/71)
    - Undated, after 1937 (Box-folder 65/72)
  - Van Norman, Julia
    - 1927 July 13 (Box-folder 65/73)
    - 1928 February 1 (Box-folder 65/74)
    - 1928 March 10 [Envelope only] (Box-folder 65/75)
    - 1928 August 18 (Box-folder 65/76)
    - 1929 March 5 (Box-folder 65/77)
    - 1932 September 28 (Box-folder 65/78)
    - 1932 October - December (Box-folder 65/79)
    - 1933 January - April (Box-folder 65/80)
    - 1933 May - July (Box-folder 66/1)
    - 1933 August - November (Box-folder 66/2)
    - 1934 February - March (Box-folder 66/3)
    - 1935 August 5 (Box-folder 66/4)
    - 1936 September - October (Box-folder 66/5)
    - 1936 November 6 (Box-folder 66/6)
    - 1936 November 11 - 1937 January 2 (Box-folder 66/7)
    - 1937 January 9 (Box-folder 66/8)
    - 1937 January 20 - April 5 (Box-folder 66/9)
    - 1937 April 15 (Box-folder 66/10)
    - 1937 April 19 - June 26 (Box-folder 66/11)
    - 1937 June 30 (Box-folder 66/12)
    - 1937 July 1 and 24, Undated (Box-folder 66/13)
    - 1937 July 31 (Box-folder 66/14)
    - 1937 August 19 (Box-folder 66/15)
    - 1938 March 22 (Box-folder 66/16)
  - Van Vechten, Carl
    - 1924-26, Undated (Box-folder 66/17)
  - Waldron, Marga
    - 1935 October 29 (Box-folder 66/18)
  - Warner Bros.
    - 1968 July (Box-folder 66/19)
  - Wattenberg, A.M.
    - 1936 December 5 (Box-folder 66/20)
    - 1937 May 29 (Box-folder 66/21)
  - Weill, Kurt
    - 1940 September (Box-folder 66/22)
    - 1941 (Box-folder 66/23)
    - 1942 (Box-folder 66/24)
    - 1943 (Box-folder 66/25)
    - 1944 February 27 (Box-folder 66/26)
  - Wilesnki, R.H.
    - 1936 (Box-folder 66/27)
  - Wilk, Max
    - 1971 October 12 (Box-folder 66/28)
    - 1971 October 29 (Box-folder 66/29)
    - 1971 November 12 (Box-folder 66/30)
    - 1971 December 13 (Box-folder 66/31)
    - 1972 January 14 (Box-folder 66/32)
    - 1972 January 18 (Box-folder 66/33)
    - 1972 January 27 (Box-folder 66/34)
    - 1972 February 15 (Box-folder 66/35)
    - 1972 November 7 (Box-folder 66/36)
  - Winsen, Felix
    - 1934 August 4 (Box-folder 66/37)
  - Wodehouse, P.G.
    - 1937 July 12 (Box-folder 66/38)
  - Wright, Mrs. Cobina
    - 1931 September 29 (Box-folder 66/39)
  - Condolence telegrams
    - A-D (Box-folder 66/40)
    - E-J (Box-folder 66/41)
    - K-R (Box-folder 66/42)
    - S-Z (Box-folder 66/43)
- Biographical Materials (Box 67-71)
  The biographical materials in the Gershwin collection are divided into three subseries. The first and second subseries, biographical materials of George and Ira Gershwin respectively, are organized alphabetically by subject matter and chronologically when appropriate. The third subseries, Lyrics on Several Occasions, is further divided into three subseries. The first subseries consists of the typescript pages appearing in paginated order. The second subseries, "Drafts," is organized in alphabetical order by subject matter. The third subseries consists solely of the galley proof.
  - George Gershwin
    - Certificate, Induction into NYU Musical Theatre Hall of Fame, 1993 November 10 (Framed)
    - Citation, National Association of Performing Artists, 1937 (Box-folder 67/1)
    - Diary of Paul Mueller, George Gershwin's butler, 1934-36, Laid in: Note by IG (2 p.); Typescript first half of diary (2 p.); Itinerary, Gershwin tour, January 13 - February 10 1936 (2 p.) (Box-folder 67/2)
    - Essays by Rosamond Walling Tirana (7), 1928, 1950, 1959, 1993, undated (Box-folder 67/3)
    - George Gershwin birth certificate, Photocopy (Box-folder 67/4)
    - Henry Botkin [Essay], Photocopy (Box-folder 67/5)
    - Hollywood Bowl Memorial Concert, 1937 September 8, 4 ticket stubs, envelope, and program (Box-folder 67/6)
    - Invitation and admission card for memorial service in Los Angeles, 1937 July 15 (Box-folder 67/7)
    - A Journey to Greatness reviews, 1936, Photocopy (Box-folder 67/8)
    - Letter to R. Gershwin from James T. White & Co., Publishers, 1941 January 30 (Box-folder 67/9)
    - List of likes and dislikes, George Gershwin holograph manuscript; 1 p. (Box-folder 67/10)
    - The Bell Telephone Hour bound script, 1959 November 20 (Box-folder 67/11)
    - Nellie Revell Radio Program broadcast script, 1933 March 13 (Box-folder 67/12)
    - Newspaper clippings from scrapbook, Some photocopies; Collected by Rose Gershwin (Box-folder 67/13)
    - Newspaper clippings (Misc.) 1937-38, 1963, 1973, undated, Some photocopies (Box-folder 68/1)
    - Newspaper clippings (Obituaries), 1937, Photocopies (Box-folder 68/2)
    - Obituary (Daily News), 1937 July 13 (Box-folder 68/3)
    - Radio broadcast script, 1942 February 8 (Box-folder 68/4)
    - Rhapsody in blue
      - Screenplay by Clifford Odets, 1942 August 28 (Box-folder 68/5)
      - Screenplay by Howard Koch, 1943 June 16 (Box-folder 68/6)
      - Screenplay by Sonia Levien, 1943 January 30 (Box-folder 69/1)
      - Story outline - Kathryn Scola and Ira Gershwin, 1941 October 24 (Box-folder 69/2)
  - Ira Gershwin
    - California, here I came, Typescript/holograph mss.; 5 drafts plus Ira Gershwin description (Box-folder 69/3)
    - University of Maryland commencement exercises program, 1966, Inscribed by Ira Gershwin to Ben Botkin (Box-folder 69/4)
  - Lyrics on Several Occasions
    - Typescript pages
      - 1-89 (Box-folder 70/1)
      - 90-195 (Box-folder 70/2)
      - 196-309 (Box-folder 70/3)
      - 310-end (Box-folder 70/4)
    - Drafts
      - Variant title pages; Foreword and acknowledgements; List of possibilities (Box-folder 70/5)
      - The not impossible he (Box-folder 70/6)
      - Divers duets (Box-folder 70/7)
      - The possessive case (Box-folder 70/8)
      - With place names (Box-folder 70/9)
      - The importunate male (Box-folder 70/10)
      - The importunate female (Box-folder 70/11)
      - A quartet of trios (Box-folder 70/12)
      - A quintet of findings (Box-folder 71/1)
      - Sextet of irreverence (Box-folder 71/2)
      - Not for a musicologist (Box-folder 71/3)
      - A set of sagas (Box-folder 71/4)
      - A gathering of guidance (Box-folder 71/5)
      - Ladies in lament (Box-folder 71/6)
      - Sound effects (Box-folder 71/7)
      - The elements of time (Box-folder 71/8)
      - Turns with terpsichore (Box-folder 71/9)
      - The state of the union (Box-folder 71/10)
      - A miscellany of acclaim (Box-folder 71/11)
      - Euphoria revisited (Box-folder 71/12)
      - Afterword (Box-folder 71/13)
      - Worksheets; Saturday review, 1959 August 29 (Box-folder 71/14)
    - Galley proof (Box-folder OV-4)
- Scrapbooks (Box 72-101)
  The scrapbooks in the Gershwin collection are divided into three subseries. The first and second subseries, "Biographical" and "Porgy and Bess" respectively, are organized in chronological order. The third subseries, "Miscellany," is organized by subject matter. Books 1-31 have also been microfilmed: #93/20013.
  - Biographical
    - Book 1, 1913-24, 60 p. + (Box-book 72/1)
    - Book 2, 1925-26, 51 p. +; Concerto in F; Rhapsody in Blue; Tell Me More; 135th Street; Lady Be Good! (English production) (Box-book 73/2)
    - Book 3, 1927-29, 54 p. +; Strike Up the Band; Funny Face; Rosalie; trip to Paris; Treasure Girl; An American in Paris; The Dybbuk; GG takes up painting; Show Girl; Strike Up the Band (2nd version) (Box-book 74/3)
    - Book 4, 1930-31, 57 p. +; Strike Up the Band; Girl Crazy; Of Thee I Sing; Delicious (Box-book 75/4)
    - Book 5, 1932-34, 54 p. +; Delicious; Of Thee I Sing; Second Rhapsody; Pardon My English; Pulitzer Prize; father's obituary; Cuban Overture; Let Them Eat Cake; Arts Club of Chicago exhibition of the George Gershwin Collection of Modern Paintings; National Tour (Box-book 76/5)
    - Book 6, 1934 August-1939, 78 p. +; Life Begins at 8:40; Porgy and Bess; Ziegfeld Follies of 1936; Suite from Porgy and Bess; Shall We Dance; GG illness and death; A Damsel in Distress; "Love Walked In" #1 tune; "Dawn of a New Day" anthem for worlds fair (Box-book 77/6)
    - Book 7, 1940-45, 63 p. +; Lady in the Dark; Girl Crazy (film); Toscanini conducts Rhapsody in Blue; Cover Girl; Lady in the Dark (film); The Firebrand of Florence; Where Do We Go From Here (film); Rhapsody in Blue (film biography) (Box-book 78/7)
    - Book 8, 1946-51, 59 p. +; Ziegfeld Follies of 1946 (film); Park Avenue; The Shocking Miss Pilgrim (film); The Barkleys of Broadway (film); death of mother Rose; death of Kurt Weill; An American in Paris (film) (Box-book 79/8)
    - Book 9, 1952-55, 70 p.; An American in Paris (film) academy awards; Of Thee I Sing (revival); Give a Girl a Break (film); Lady in the Dark (TV); A Star is Born (film); The Country Girl (film) (Box-book 80/9)
    - Book 10, 1956-59, 53 p.; Funny Face (film); Ewen biography "The Magic of Gershwin"; Ira's illness; Bell Telephone Hour-"Gershwin" (TV); Ella Fitzgerald Gershwin concert and recording (Box-book 81/10)
    - Book 11, 1960-62, 52 p.; Oh, Kay (revival); Of Thee I Sing (production); Girl Crazy; The George and Ira Gershwin Songbook; The Gershwin Years (TV) (Box-book 82/11)
    - Book 12, 1963-64, 50 p. +; ASCAP plaque on birthplace; Oh, Kay!; 17 trunk songs unearthed by Ira; The Songs of Harold Arlen (TV); fire at Chappell's in London; death of Cole Porter; Kiss Me Stupid (film) (Box-book 83/12)
    - Book 13, 1965-67, 61 p. +; Kiss Me Stupid (film); When the Boys Meet the Girls (film); George Gershwin's Theater (An Unusual Entertainment); Honorary degree for Ira from University of Maryland; Lady in the Dark (Pasadena Playhouse); Star! (film) (Box-book 84/13)
    - Book 14, 1968-72, 100 p.; Lady Be Good! (London); Star! (film); Of Thee I Sing (revival); Who Cares (Balancine ballet); Gershwin Festival (University of Miami); Ira elected to the Songwriters Hall of Fame; 'S Wonderful, 'S Marvelous, 'S Gershwin (TV); Of Thee I Sing (TV); Gershwin exhibit at Library of Congress; George Gershwin stamp issued (Box-book 85/14)
    - Book 15, 1973-75, 82 p.; George Gershwin stamp; 75th anniversary of George's birth; Gershwin Film Retrospective; 50th Anniversary of Rhapsody in Blue; Lady Be Good! (at Goodspeed); Uris Theater renamed The Gershwin; "Tribute to Ira Gershwin" Benefit; "Mr. Words," a musical salute to Ira Gershwin; "Our Love is Here to Stay" with Steve and Eydie (TV) (Box-book 86/15)
    - Book 16, 1976-82, 124 p.; Lyrics and Lyricists "The Lyrics of Ira Gershwin"; Tip Toes (at Goodspeed); Let 'Em Eat Cake (Berkshires); Funny Face (Studio Arena and Goodspeed); "By Ira...By Goerge" Tribute at Carnegie Hall; Gershwin Concert ballet by Jerome Robbins; "Celebrating the Gershwins" at Brooklyn College; Secaucus scores found (Box-book 87/16)
    - Book 17, 1983 January-May, 96 p.; Restored version of A Star is Born; Rosalie (concert revival); My One and Only (Box-book 88/17)
    - Book 18, 1983 May-August, 92 p.; My One and Only; Gershwin Tony Award and tribute; renaming the Uris Theater to the Gershwin; Michael Feinstein interview with Ira; restored version of A Star is Born (Box-book 89/18)
    - Book 19, 1983 August-1984 October, 100 p.; Ira's death; Hang On To Me; Oh, Kay! (at Chichester Festival); Strike Up the Band (revival); Gershwin Room at the Library of Congress planned (Box-book 90/19)
    - Book 20, 1984 October-1985 December, 84 p.; Ira's death; Gershwin Night at the Library of Congress; My One and Only; Gershwin Congressional Medal (Box-book 91/20)
    - Book 21, 1986 January- August, 32 p.; My One and Only; George and Ira Gershwin awarded the Academy's Trustee Award at the Grammys; Girl Crazy (at Seattle Rep) (Box-book 91/21)
  - Porgy and Bess
    - Book 1, 1935-1954 July, 172 p.; Original production of Porgy and Bess, tours, 1942 revival, 1952 revival (that goes on to European tour and returns to Broadway) (Box-book 92/22)
    - Book 2, 1954 August-1956, 72 p.; Porgy and Bess in Paris, Zagreb, Yugoslavia, Israel, Alexandria, Athens, Cairo, La Scala, Milan, Rome, Lausanne, Geneva, Rio de Janeiro, Buenos Aires, Russia, West Germany, Poland, Norway, and Czechoslovakia; Truman Capote's "The Muses are Heard" (about Russian tour) (Box-folder 93/23)
    - Book 3, 1957-59, 52 p.; Porgy and Bess film; various recordings (Box-folder 94/24)
    - Book 4, 1960-65, 50 p.; Porgy and Bess film in London; NY City Center Light Opera production; Russian student production; New Zealand production; Coconut Grove Playhouse production; Vienna production (Box-folder 94/25)
    - Book 5, 1966-76, 62 p.; Porgy and Bess Israeli production; Charleston production; Berlin production; Serbian production; Lisbon, Portugal production; LA Civic Light Opera production; Atlanta production; recording with Cleveland Orchestra; Houston Opera production (tour) (Box-folder 95/26)
    - Book 6, 1977-84, 108 p.; Porgy and Bess Houston Opera (tour continued); 1978 European tour; "Todd Duncan: A Mighty Voice" (TV); Houston Opera revival at Radio City; various other productions (Box-folder 96/27)
    - Book 7, 1985-1986 August, 64 p.; Porgy and Bess 50th anniversary; Metropolitan Opera production; Dubose Heyward Centennial Celebration; 50th anniversary production at Charleston, South Carolina; Glyndebourne Festival Opera 1986 production (Box-folder 97/28)
  - Miscellany
    - Miscellaneous clippings: Volume 1, 1947-71, 44 p.; Articles and obituaries on other composers, lyricists, writers, performers, the music industry, etc. (Box-folder 98/29)
    - Miscellaneous clippings: Volume 2, 1972-?, 102 p.; Articles and obituaries on other composers, lyricists, writers, performers, the music industry, etc. (Box-folder 98/30)
    - Ira gershwin "Lyrics on several occasions", 1959-77, 48 p. (Box-folder 99/31)
    - First scrapbooks
      - George Gershwin, 1909?-1920, 36 p. + (Box-folder 100/32)
      - Ira gershwin, 1908-10, 143 p. (Box-folder 100/33)
    - George Gershwin memorial scrapbook, 1937 July 11-August 11, 560 p. (Box-folder 101/34)
- Iconography (Box 102-108)
  The iconography in the Gershwin Collection is divided into two subseries, "Photographs" and "Paintings and drawings."
  - Photographs
    The photographs of the Gershwin Collection are divided into five subseries. The first, fourth and fifth subseries, "Photographs taken by George Gershwin," "Photographs belonging to George Gershwin," and "Miscellaneous" photographs, are organized alphabetically by subject's name. The second and third subseries, "Photographs of George Gershwin and family and friends," "Photographs of Ira, Arthur, Frances Gershwin (Godowsky), and other family members and friends," is organized in chronological order.
    - Photographs taken by George Gershwin
      - Irving Berlin (Box-folder 102/I-1)
      - Irving Berlin (Box-folder 102/I-2)
      - Henry Botkin (Box-folder 102/I-3)
      - Gloria Braggioti (Box-folder 102/I-4)
      - William Daly (Box-folder 102/I-5)
      - William Daly (Box-folder 102/I-6)
      - Ruby Elzy (Box-folder 102/I-7)
      - George Gershwin, (Self portrait) (Box-folder 102/I-8)
      - George Gershwin and Irving Berlin (Box-folder 102/I-9)
      - George Gershwin and Irving Berlin (Box-folder 102/I-10)
      - George Gershwin and Irving Berlin (Box-folder 102/I-11)
      - Leonore Gershwin, 1936, Inscribed on mounting board by George Gershwin (Box-folder OV-2/1)
      - Mrs. Rose Gershwin (Box-folder 102/I-12)
      - Leopold Godowsky, Sr. (Box-folder 102/I-13)
      - Leopold Godowsky, Sr. (Box-folder 102/I-14)
      - Leopold Godowsky, Sr. (Box-folder 102/I-15)
      - Kaye Halle (Box-folder 102/I-16)
      - Jerome Kern, Painting by George Gershwin (Box-folder 102/I-17)
      - Emily Paley (Box-folder 102/I-18)
      - David Alfaro Siqueiros (Box-folder 102/I-19)
      - David Alfaro Siqueiros and Unidentified (Box-folder 102/I-20)
      - Kay Swift (Box-folder 102/I-21)
      - Andrea Warburg and Kay Warburg (Box-folder 102/I-22)
    - Photographs of George Gershwin and family and friends
      - Family: Arthur Gershwin, Maid, George Gershwin, Rose Gershwin, and Ira Gershwin, ca. 1900, Brooklyn, NY (Box-folder 103/II-1)
      - Family: George Gershwin, Arthur Gershwin, Ira Gershwin and Rose Lagowitz, 1912, Coney Island (Box-folder 103/II-2)
      - Arthur and George Gershwin, Coney Island, 1912 (Box-folder 103/II-2a)
      - George Gershwin, Atlantic City, 1916 (Box-folder OV-2/2)
      - George Gershwin, ca. 1918 (Box-folder 103/II-3)
      - George Gershwin, ca. 1918 (Box-folder 103//II-4)
      - George Gershwin at piano (Box-folder 103/II-5)
      - George Gershwin at piano, 1919, (From Illustrated News) (Box-folder 103/II-5a)
      - George Gershwin (Box-folder 103/II-6)
      - Unidentified woman and man, Al Jolson, George Gershwin, ca. 1920 (Box-folder 103/II-7)
      - George Gershwin ca. 1920 (Box-folder 103/II-7a)
      - George Gershwin at Pall Mall Court, London, 1925 May (Box-folder 103/II-7b)
      - George Gershwin, July 1925 (Box-folder 103/II-8)
      - George Gershwin, Whitehall Hotel, NY, 1925 (Box-folder 103/II-9)
      - Deems Taylor, Ferde Grofé, Paul Whiteman, Blossom Seely, and George Gershwin, 1925 (Box-folder 103/II-10)
      - George Gershwin, 1927, By Edward Steichen (Box-folder 103/II-11)
      - George Gershwin, (third from left) (Box-folder 103/II-12)
      - George Gershwin, Potsdamer Platz, Berlin, 1928 April (Box-folder 103/II-13)
      - Back row: Ira Gershwin, Leonore Gershwin, George Gershwin, Emmerich Kalman, Henrietta Malkiel, Vienna, 1928 April 28 (Box-folder 103/II-14)
      - Franz Lehar and George Gershwin, Vienna, 1928 May (Box-folder 103/II-15)
      - Ray Hornikel, James Rosenberg, George Gershwin, Fritz Reiner, Richard Crooks, Cincinnatti, 1929 February 28 (Box-folder 103/II-16)
      - George Gershwin, Unidentified woman (Box-folder 103/II-17)
      - George Gershwin, (at right) (Box-folder 103/II-18)
      - George Gershwin, (at right) (Box-folder 103/II-19)
      - Richard Rodgers, Justine Johnson, George Gershwin, Jules Glaenzer (Box-folder 103/II-20)